Winter arrived at our home
in the forest once again.
The snow piles up every year.
So we step away from our
farming lifestyle for the season.
Getting through winter with the food and
wood we prepared earlier in the year.
With our new villages,
we had many more mouths to feed.
We'd worried if we'd prepared enough, but...
We aren't getting through our food stores?
Yes, well, we're consuming some, of course.
But hardly enough.
We're using less than a third
of what we estimated.
That little?
They seem conditioned by
their circumstances until now...
Morning
Hot Water
Noon
...and so they eat as little as possible.
Jerky
Night
Hot Water
Modest living is to be commended,
but this level of restraint
is an issue of its own.
We've told them there is no need
for such moderation, yet still...
Maybe we can ask them to eat the meat
and vegetables that will spoil otherwise.
Good thinking.
That might change their minds.
I'll bring word to them now.
We'll need to examine our stores.
Mamu?
What's wrong?
Do the nyunyu daphne need anything?
Nothing.
They never need anything!
And that's a problem?
They don't need food.
In tree form, they can withstand the cold.
Peaceful.
Every now and then
I dig them out of the snow, but...
Help!
I was so happy to be put in charge of them,
but they never need anything from me!
You might say their minds are at ease
because you're around.
There is something...
Yes? What might it be?!
The minotaurs have a request
of the nyunyu daphne.
Yes?!
They would like them to wear clothing
when they are out.
Serenity.
Oh, they sometimes forget to wear
clothing when in human form.
But don't worry!
I'll tell them to be more careful!
I'm glad that was a simple problem...
I guess?
Winter time...
calls for winter food!
That looks properly steamed!
I smell rice!
Making something bizarre again, I imagine?
You've got sharp eyes!
Or noses?
That looks like quite a lot.
Will you be making rice balls?
I wonder how many this will make.
Actually, this is for...
Oh, dear sisters, how wrong you are.
What's gotten into you?
They are clearly preparing
to ferment something.
Fermentation
No, no, we're about to do
something different.
What's going on here?
It appears they're making
some new type of food.
Now then...
With this mortar and pestle,
we will make mochi.
Never heard of those.
Is the tool in his hand the pestle?
And the rice will become mochi?
Growing rice was quite complicated.
But there is such a variety of ways to eat it.
This rice is different from the usual.
It's specifically for making mochi.
Raising Seedlings
Mochi mochi mochi mochi...
Mochi mochi mochi mochi
I never knew there were different types.
Now then...
Ready.
Here goes!
Yah!
Go.
Hup!
Hah!
Go.
Hrmf!
Rmm!
Go.
I was expecting something more spectacular.
Turns out it's all quite simple.
Hoof...
Phew, this really tires you out.
We simply need to smash it, yes?
I wanna try!
Be my guests.
But... go easy on it.
Ready?
Here goes!
Pat.
Squish squish.
Squeeze!
Hang on, I don't like the look of that!
And so it became something else entirely.
So we tried again.
Everyone who came when they
heard the ruckus took turns.
And eventually it felt
more like the real thing.
My apologies.
Sorry for the wait!
Here's a special explosive that's just
weak enough that the house won't blow up!
No explosions, please.
After all our troubles, we finally had
mochi ready for flavoring.
Sweet and savory in sugary soy sauce.
The classic roasted soy powder.
And zunda, made with smashed edamame.
Oh, what an intriguing consistency.
So stretchy!
We also boiled up red beans to make zenzai!
Just what you need to warm up on a cold day.
That's hot!
Burning hot!
Try some of these if you'd like.
Oh, kusamochi!
I've added fragrant herbs from the forest.
Oh, these are excellent.
Even better than the mugwort back home.
I'm so glad you like it.
Picking herbs is quite a trial.
You need to be prepared
for them to fight back.
Herbs can fight?
It's nothing like a rice ball.
Rice is so peculiar.
Oh, feasting away, are we?
Donovan, what's that you've got?
I heard you were cooking up rice,
so I brought something to go with it.
Much appreciated.
Oh, I know what this is.
Home-brewed sake!
Alcohol?
Seems like!
Caught your attention fast, huh?
Drink up and enjoy!
Pretty good, right?
This is so good!
Mochi-making caught on
as a form of winter exercise
whenever the weather permitted.
And the best mochi-maker among us was...
Oh, hello.
...Gordon, the minotaur.
There's no need to use force.
Simply let the pestle fall
under its own weight.
Exactly.
Farming Life in Another World 2.
Please!
I wish to take you as my wife!
I'm sorry, who are you, exactly?
Forgive me.
I am head of House Britoa of the
Demonic Kingdom of Galgardo.
My name is Grattz Britoa.
Please, might I have your name?
Minotaur
Ronana
I am Ronana.
A minotaur woman from Village Two
and an imposing man in armor...
What's going on here?
Do forgive us for troubling you.
Demonic Kingdom of Galgardo - Demon Lord's Castle
The Great Tree Village?
For what sudden business?
One of the Demon Lord's Four Great Generals - Beezel
Relations with the village
are vital for our kingdom.
One of the Demon Lord's Four Great Generals - Grattz
Why should I not witness it for myself?
Well...
One of the Demon Lord's Four Great Generals - Beezel
My curiosity grows!
One of the Demon Lord's Four Great Generals - Grattz
I see...
One of the Demon Lord's Four Great Generals - Beezel
He would have it no other way,
and this is what came of bringing him here.
Love at first sight, or so he says.
Are you the mayor of this village?
Yeah, the name's Hiraku.
And your conditions?
Huh?
Tell me what you require of me
to take Ronana as my wife!
She says I must ask your permission.
Can I have a moment?
Is that the normal way to take a wife here?
It's not entirely not-normal.
But parents often decide on
their child's spouse.
At least for the first two or three wives.
One day, a gallant man of nobility and
a girl from a remote village came together...
Here we go...
Lovers from two different worlds.
They are torn apart.
As they escape on a dark moonless night...
the evil hand of the mayor closes in!
Roar!
It's like a story out of fairy tales.
Right. Let's all just say that made sense.
Look, I see that you're sincere,
but what matters most is what she wants.
If Ronana doesn't want to be married,
I'm afraid I must refuse.
I need only make her say so?
But you can't force her.
No threats or commands.
Take your time, think it over,
and decide if he's right for you.
Very well.
Do that and you'll have
no complaints from me.
Well then, Miss Ronana...
Yes?
What would you have me do?
Well...
The perfect match can come out of nowhere.
Personally, I hope the best for them both.
Demonic Kingdom of Galgardo - Demon Lord's Castle
We've agreed to start by exchanging letters.
But I cannot keep her from my mind.
One of the Demon Lord's Four Great Generals - Beezel
While I stand here,
One of the Demon Lord's Four Great Generals - Randan
some other man might steal her away!
One of the Demon Lord's Four Great Generals - Grattz
I wish to be by her side!
I resign from my position
among the great generals!
Spare us this foolishness.
You are commander of the kingdom's militia.
Yes, and you cannot leave
such a post on a mere whim!
My brother will serve in my stead.
That is irresponsible!
I care not!
You are a disgrace!
I choose to live for love!
Fine, I quit too!
Feel free!
I beg to differ.
Well? How did we do?
We made these pickles as well.
Oh, I think you did excellently.
I have that pot you needed fixed.
Thank you.
Wish we had something
to really make this dish sing.
Sing?
Can food do that?
Sing...
Sing?
Waaa!
Ooo hoo!
Sorry, I meant that metaphorically.
I meant like seaweed-dark, thin...
And how strong?
How... strong?
It comes from the sea, like kelp.
Usually wrapped around food.
It wraps its food?
Thin Dark Threat
C. Weed
How violent.
I think it grows close to the seashore.
It's harvested when it's cold, I think.
Some famous person on
a TV show said as much.
If it comes from the sea,
we ought ask Michael.
A trip to Shashaato it is, then!
Then, a few days later...
Thank you as always for
your continued patronage.
Sorry to bring you out here in this cold.
Spare it no thought!
I would travel through fire, water,
and the icy northern winds to do trade.
Zoom!
So cold!
Now, we do not consume things
such as this seaweed you requested,
so I am not entirely sure
I have brought what you desire.
Truth is, I don't know
all that much about it either.
But I'll give it a try.
First, you use a knife to chop it.
That should do it.
Then you separate it in some water.
And spread it in a wooden frame like this.
Is that enough?
This almost looks like...
the weeds that grow in the forest shade.
You have a point.
I suppose there's a reason
it's called seaweed.
SEA
SEA WEED
Once it's spread thin,
you remove the frame.
Then we let it dry.
We leave it like this?
We should dry it outside.
No, we'll leave this to our helping hands.
Here I go, Tia.
Whenever you're ready.
Dry! Dry!
Drying
Goodbye, moisture!
The convenience of magic.
We processed the seaweed you brought us.
This is the same stuff?
Is it fabric? Paper, maybe?
I thought it was to be food?
Is it eaten as-is?
Hang on!
First, you add heat,
and crisp it up!
Apparently this makes it easier to digest.
I'd rather not upset their stomachs.
Has it taken on a new shade?
I've never smelled anything like it.
And once it's ready,
this is the only way to go!
What more could you ask for?
Now this takes me back!
How is it?
I think I might cry.
Is it that good?!
The saltiness is a perfect match.
At last, we get a taste!
I love how easy it is to hold.
We have roasted seaweed.
We have a brazier.
It must be done!
Fried mochi in seaweed!
Mochi was good already, but now
it's crispy, crunchy, and flavorful!
Good mayor, if you so wish it,
I can see to it my people harvest
and process this seaweed for you.
In exchange, I might ask you trade us
some of the ingredients for this mochi.
It's not something we can do right away,
as we'd need to grow more mochi rice.
But I will raise the topic with my people.
Much appreciated.
The ingredients keep for long and need
only be cooked and dressed in sauce.
Yes, this will be a fine money-maker.
I've heard you have alcohol
made from rice as well?
Hands off our alcohol!
Very well.
Farming...
Life...
in Another World 2!
We have rice. We have seaweed.
Something in my very soul calls out to me.
"Make sushi!" it screams.
Why must you fan it?
Honestly? No idea.
But this looks more the part.
First, you take freshly made rice and
add in vinegar mixed with salt and sugar.
Salt
Sugar
Vinegar
Then you wrap up the ingredients you have.
Many imagine nigiri
when they think of sushi.
But the people of this world
are averse to raw fish.
So instead, we're making thick sushi rolls
with no raw ingredients.
The dextrous mountain elves
made our sushi mats for us.
Once you place the ingredients on the rice,
you use the mat to roll it up.
Once it's wrapped, you cut it with a knife.
Hrmm, it's tough to make these round.
Finished.
Impressive, honestly.
Now to mix things up.
We have mayonnaise,
so we'll make salad rolls.
We don't have imitation crab meat,
so instead we'll use the real thing.
What extravagance!
There's no way this doesn't taste incredible!
I just needed to check if it tasted okay.
This one didn't roll well anyway, so...
Well, it appears I've improperly cut this.
The angle is all off here.
It is poor manners to sneak food that way.
Sorry.
Wow, so this is sushi?
It looks so lovely.
The tart smell put me off,
but it goes surprisingly well.
The vinegar might help it
keep in lunch boxes.
Why is that?
Vinegar helps to eliminate bacteria.
Vinegar
It does?
And here they were,
hoping to ferment things.
I'll avenge you!
After all that, winter is coming to an end.
But even as the snow melts,
it does still get cold.
Most years we struggle to decide
when to start farming again, but...
It's too early.
From now on, we'll follow Igu's advice.
There's something else I hope
to prepare before spring.
You want to carry decorations around?
Hanging explosives to set off around town?
Getting chased by rampaging bulls?
Why would anyone do such?
When you put it that way,
I'm not exactly sure.
What other customs are there?
Well...
Now that we have Village Two,
Village Three, and all our new residents,
A festival!
FESTIVAL
I thought maybe we could start
a new festival for the village.
It's all like, "Yay! Festival!"
I tried telling them about
and then more "Hooray!"
all the festivals I knew.
Throwing tomatoes at each other?
Chasing cheese rolling down a hill?
Running around with pudding?
I'm sorry, despite your efforts,
we just do not understand.
No, it's my fault for giving
such weird examples.
What sort of festivals are you familiar with?
The sort to welcome in
the new year or new harvest.
Oh, I know some like that.
What do you do at those festivals?
We set up a pyopyo in the middle of town.
Wait, not a moomoo?
Don't you mean the fall chomuchomu?
What? No...
Chomuchomu
I'm not following a word...
But if this world has its own festivals,
maybe I should let them plan one for me.
In my homeland, pyopyo leaves the center
of town to attack the homes of the rich.
Pyopyo only digs a hole.
Moomoo attacks.
Attacks how?
Under cover.
Moomoo would never!
They all have different interpretations.
According to the official position-
Who gave them the right
to decide anything?
Moomoo stands for justice!
They all seem to disagree.
Moomoo is all about the crazed sneak attacks.
Any chance we can combine this all into one?
I doubt it.
Moomoo defeats all evil!
Each region appears to have
quite different takes.
Moomoo is the sneakiest attacker.
Each region appears to have
quite different takes.
Moomoo is the sneakiest attacker.
The weak-kneed moomoo is best.
I agree.
Nothing was coming together,
so we had them each write down their
local traditions so we could draw lots.
Okay! Only one winner.
Let's see...
Martial Arts Competition
How do they compete?
By pitting fighting styles
against each other.
Oh, not just a demonstration or something?
I'm glad you picked something simple.
Let's get right to planning the competition.
Okay!
We cannot let this be anything but incredible!
Not feeling great about picking
something so violent...
But maybe it will just be like
a school sports day?
Kind of?
Next time
Martial Arts Competition
Episode 4